<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ProcessStaffingResource 
			systemEnvironmentCode="Production" 
			releaseID="3.2" 
			languageCode="en-US" 
			xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.hr-xml.org/3  ../Developer/BODs/ProcessStaffingResource.xsd" 
			xmlns="http://www.hr-xml.org/3" 
			xmlns:oa="http://www.openapplications.org/oagis/9" 
			xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
            xmlns:ext="http://resumeparsingco.com">
	<oa:ApplicationArea>
		<oa:CreationDateTime>2009-10-17T10:09:02.01Z</oa:CreationDateTime>
		<oa:BODID>PC2009-11-17-016</oa:BODID>
	</oa:ApplicationArea>
	<DataArea>
		<oa:Process>
			<oa:ActionCriteria>
				<oa:ActionExpression actionCode="Add">/ProcessStaffingResource/DataArea/StaffingResource</oa:ActionExpression>
			</oa:ActionCriteria>
		</oa:Process>
		<StaffingResource majorVersionID="1" minorVersionID="0">
			<DocumentID schemeID="ResourceID" schemeAgencyID="JustAVMSInc.com">99999111888</DocumentID>
			<AlternateDocumentID schemeID="CandidateID" schemeAgencyID="GenericJobBoardCoInc.com">88811199999</AlternateDocumentID>
			<AlternateDocumentID schemeID="ResumeID" schemeAgencyID="ParseMeCo, Inc.">11188899999</AlternateDocumentID>
			<StaffingResourceStatusCode>Active</StaffingResourceStatusCode>
			<StaffingRate>
                    <oa:Amount currencyID="USD">150</oa:Amount>
			 	    <PayRateIntervalCode>Hour</PayRateIntervalCode>
			</StaffingRate>
			<ResourcePerson>
				<PersonName>
					<FormattedName>Wayne Gray</FormattedName>
					<oa:GivenName>Wayne</oa:GivenName>
					<FamilyName>Gray</FamilyName>
				</PersonName>
				<Communication>
					<ChannelCode>Telephone</ChannelCode>
					<UseCode>Business</UseCode>
					<oa:AreaDialing>408</oa:AreaDialing>
					<oa:DialNumber>739-3609</oa:DialNumber>
				</Communication>
				<Communication>
					<ChannelCode>Email</ChannelCode>
					<UseCode>Personal</UseCode>
					<oa:URI>w-gray@comcast.net</oa:URI>
				</Communication>
				<Communication>
				<Address>
					<oa:AddressLine sequence="1">1664 Mariani Dr</oa:AddressLine>
					<oa:CityName>Sunnyvale</oa:CityName>
					<oa:CountrySubDivisionCode listID="US States">CA</oa:CountrySubDivisionCode>
					<CountryCode>US</CountryCode>
					<oa:PostalCode>94087</oa:PostalCode>
				</Address>
				</Communication>
			</ResourcePerson>
			<ResourceProfile>
			<ExecutiveSummary>A seasoned, highly motivated, team oriented senior executive whose highly successful career includes a track record of creating several hundred million dollars in new wealth and shareholder value. As a C-Level manager for 5 companies, my focus on strategic innovation and execution excellence has repeatedly generated more than 1000% shareholder ROI in venture funded start - ups. A serial entrepreneur with more than 24 years of experience in application, middleware, and system software design and development including; 11 years of experience in Executive and Senior Management positions as CEO, CTO, V.P. of Engineering, Director of Software Development, and Senior Project Manager; 13 years experience as Chief Software Architect and Engineering Lead - developing value propositions from clouds to code; Proficient in a wide array of  &#197;&quot;best practice &#194; business processes, development lifecycles, and Object Oriented engineering.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS:

INFOSEC Summary: 10 years of experience developing industry leading INFOSEC products including IDS/IPS, firewall, anti-virus, deception/honeypot, threat management, and event correlation systems. Focused on digital security, networking, and communications security, intrusion detection and prevention, asset availability and assurance, business continuity, network acceleration, wireless and distributed computing, cryptography/cryptanalysis, developing decision support systems, and architecting secure infrastructures and policies.

Founder/Co-founder of 5 software companies including ICCi, HighTech Expression, Mira Technology, Intuitive Solutions, and NLO. First round employee for Thoughtware Computer Company, AirSoft Inc., and AlertSoft, Inc.

Successfully negotiated 4 M&amp;As from both buyer and seller positions; two over $100 million and the largest software company acquisition of 2002 (Surpass to Borland, AirSoft to Shiva, AlertSoft to AtomicTangerine, Recourse to Symantec). Managed two spin-outs (HighTech Expressions from ThoughtWare, AlertSoft from SRI).
Grew several start-ups from inception, through pre-IPO series D round funding; grew three start-ups to over one hundred employees; Elevated several companies from obscurity
to top positions in the  &#197;&quot;Gartner Magic Quadrant &#194; through development of new visions, strategic planning, corporate development, and improved execution; Served
as member and/or participant on several company boards to provide business model development, manage M&amp;A and venture funding efforts. Served in leadership and management positions for some of the world&apos;s largest software companies including projects involving thousands
 of engineers, Q/A, and support staff  (IBM&apos;s OS/2), to mid-sized projects involving hundreds of engineers (Network Associates, Borland International), to small start-up companies (Recourse, AlertSoft, Intuitive Solutions, WAI, AirSoft, HighTech Expressions, Thoughtware).
 
Managed geographically dispersed global project teams developing market leadership technologies for multi-platform international deployment. Fundamentally responsible for developing and shipping over 40 commercially successful internationally distributed applications, languages, operating systems, device drivers, &amp; Web sites including: Trigger, the Management Advantage, the Animated Card, the Career Navigator, OS/2, Presentation Manager, Quattro Pro, Paradox, The Virtual Office, AirAccess, Powerburst, HyperDrive, TrialLock, SystemVoyeur, Motorola&apos;s FLEX 2-way wireless paging systems, McAfee Anti-Virus, NetShield NT/NetWare, Phoenix power management BIOS, FWB DriveUp, Network Labs Online/Cisco CCIE Web Site, CyberCop Monitor IDS, PGP Security Management Reporting, Event Orchastrator Security Management Framework, ManTrap Deception Sensor, ManHunt Intrusion Prevention System, and GreenBorder Trusted Computing System.
   
Provided consulting services to Silicon Valley industry leaders to manage projects, architect and develop shrink-wrapped products and appliances, enterprise, and multi-tier component based applications, device drivers, and web sites,  port legacy systems and lead migrations into new technologies, build and mentor engineering staff, and turn failing projects into successful ventures. Routinely author/publish white papers, articles, reports, and presentations.

Received numerous awards including Technical Excellence, Best in Class, Top 10 Start-up Founder&apos;s awards, and the patents detailed below.

Engineering Summary: Engineering expertise refined through more than two decades of technology and industry evolution beginning with application, driver, BIOS, and Operating System development in assembly language (Intel/Motorola), structured language programming using native APIs (C/BASIC/Pascal/FORTRAN/RPG/ DOS/Win32/WinSock),

Object Oriented Programming (OOPs) with frameworks and class libraries (C++/Java/ MFC/AWT), distributed application development using location transparent components and reusable binaries (COM/CORBA/ATL/OLEDB), Internet aware/Web enabled application and middleware development using N-tier systems and declarative programming infrastructures (DNA/ADO/ASP/SQL) culminating in cross-language inheritance and managed code development (C#/.NET).

INVENTIONS AND MARKET INNOVATIONS:

Introduced several new market categories and invented technologies for commercialization that resulted in the birth of four companies and the generation of several hundred million dollars in revenue including:

Automated analysis of digital evidence. Became the value proposition for Stanford Research Institute&apos;s SDL spin-out AlertSoft. A probabilistic reasoning system employing
a network model of joint probability distributions that define a belief state of causal relationships for incident identification and tracking between multiple sensors.

Multi-sensor alert correlation and normalization. An application framework developed for Network Associate that became the backbone of their security infrastructure and provided a framework to integrate the company&apos;s INFOSEC products into a more effective holistic solution for network security.

Remote access acceleration. A technology based on a low-overhead transfer protocol that maintained cache coherency for disconnected, low availability, and slow speed WAN/LAN links. Resulted in the birth of AirSoft and was the forerunner of modern caching proxy servers.

The Intelligent Document Expert Automation System (IDEAS). The forerunner of user interfaces based on probabilistic expert systems and machine learning. IDEAS employs adaptive algorithms  to monitor user interactions with data and then optimally organizes and files the data in an intelligent file cabinet. Resulted in the birth of Intuitive Solutions Inc.

Fluid cell animation for low throughput systems. Commercialized into the first fully surfaced apparent 3D interactive models presented in real-time on the PC. Resulted in the birth of HighTech Expressions  which produced the first commercial broadcast animation, animated cards, animated computer assistants, and animated Computer Based Training (CBT) systems based on PC technologies and IBM Vision platforms.
</ExecutiveSummary>
				<EmploymentHistory>
					<EmployerHistory>
						<OrganizationName>GreenBorder, Inc</OrganizationName>
						<PositionHistory>
							<PositionTitle>Chief Technology Officer</PositionTitle>
							<ResourceRelationshipCode>Employee</ResourceRelationshipCode>
							<PositionLocation>
								<ReferenceLocation>
									<oa:CityName>Mountain View</oa:CityName>
									<oa:CountrySubDivisionCode listID="US States">CA</oa:CountrySubDivisionCode>
									<CountryCode>US</CountryCode>
								</ReferenceLocation>
							</PositionLocation>
							<EmploymentPeriod>
								<StartDate>
									<FormattedDateTime>2002</FormattedDateTime>
								</StartDate>
								<EndDate>
									<DateText>until present</DateText>
								</EndDate>
								<!-- CurrentIndicator - indicates that this is a position currently held 
                                       at the time the information was reported -->
								<CurrentIndicator>true</CurrentIndicator>
							</EmploymentPeriod>
							<oa:Description> 2002  &quot; Present   Chief Technology Officer
  GreenBorder, Inc.; Mountain View CA

A leading developer of Trusted Computing Systems. Creators of  &#197;&quot;Protection without Detection &#194; - the first host (application/language agnostic) security system to use virtualization instead of detection &amp; response to prevent intrusions and malware propagation while ensuring the integrity of the system.

Corporate Officer brought onboard as part of the close of series B funding. Originally assumed the title of VP of Engineering tasked to provide tactical and strategic
leadership, build the product development/delivery infrastructure, evolve the product prototype to GA, and develop the long term roadmap. Responsible for both execution and strategic development, I assumed the role of CTO after successfully re-architecting the product line and completing beta. Served both inbound and outbound roles while reorganizing Marketing and supporting BusDev and launch activities. Managed Engineering, Release, QA, Pubs, Professional Services/SEs, and R&amp;D departments; Responsible for 5 direct reports (Director of Engineering, Director of Marketing, and 3 Senior Managers) and a staff of 30. Reported to the CEO. Accomplishments include the following:     Re-architected the product line to elevate the product from a lab prototype to an  &#197;&quot;Enterprise Class &#194; solution including redesigning the core components to be application agnostic and forward compatible with evolving systems, adding a management server for large scale configuration, management, and reporting, and improving the value proposition with hardened security, greater scope, less user/behavior impact, improved ease-of-use, and better performance.
 
Improved execution and coordinated cross-functional teams by developing and instigating better processes and creating a new engineering culture. Increased productivity by developing new core competencies, establishing standards of discipline, and performing critical path analysis and resource leveling. Optimized technical solutions by driving decomposition, definition, integration, and verification efforts. Created predictable and measurable quality using metrics to project and track schedules.
   
Defined and managed the IP strategy/portfolio including 17 patents; monitored emerging technologies, market, and industry trends and invented technologies resulting in 11 patents.
Supported Marketing efforts by developing value propositions, identifying requirements/features/benefits and working with the PMM to draft the PRD and complete market analysis, business case, positioning, and pricing. Supported Marcom/PR activities by authoring datasheets, whitepapers, and corporate presentations, serving as the company evangelist at speaking engagements and as a keynote speaker at industry trade shows, briefing analysts and investment bankers, and training sales teams and channel partners.
   
Supported BusDev efforts by identifying partners and technology synergies, negotiating M&amp;A potentials with Symantec, Computer Associates, EDS, and Microsoft, developing channel partnerships to establish multi-million dollar predictable and recurring revenue streams.
Supported Sales as the technical point of contact for all Fortune 200 customer negotiations.</oa:Description>
							<UserArea>
								<ext:ProcessingComment>[*CO. NAME PROBABILITY = 10240; *POS. TITLE PROBABILITY = 309] [*Offset of farthest data found = 82]</ext:ProcessingComment>
							</UserArea>
						</PositionHistory>
					</EmployerHistory>
					<EmployerHistory>
						<OrganizationName>Recourse Technologies, Inc.</OrganizationName>
						<PositionHistory>
							<PositionTitle>Vice President, Engineering</PositionTitle>
							<ResourceRelationshipCode>Employee</ResourceRelationshipCode>
							<PositionLocation>
								<ReferenceLocation>
									<oa:CityName>Redwood City</oa:CityName>
									<oa:CountrySubDivisionCode listID="US States">CA</oa:CountrySubDivisionCode>
									<CountryCode>US</CountryCode>
								</ReferenceLocation>
							</PositionLocation>
							<EmploymentPeriod>
								<StartDate>
									<FormattedDateTime>2001</FormattedDateTime>
								</StartDate>
								<EndDate>
									<FormattedDateTime>2002</FormattedDateTime>
								</EndDate>
							</EmploymentPeriod>
							<oa:Description>2001 - 2002    Vice President, Engineering
Recourse Technologies, Inc.; Redwood City CA

Creators of the first Protocol Anomaly Detection system, gigabit then multi-gigabit Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention System (NIDS) and honeypot early warning systems. Acquired by Symantec Corp. (Nasdaq: SYMC).

Executive Staff member and manager of Product Development, Delivery, &amp; R&amp;D departments; Managed a direct staff of six Senior Managers and Directors and an extended staff of 40. Reported to the CEO

Responsible for defining Recourse&apos;s corporate and product strategy, staffing, retaining, and managing the Engineering, Q/A, Release, Sustaining, Lab, and Technical Communications departments, developing and presenting product strategies/roadmaps, activity, and operating/capital budgets to the Board of Directors.

Transformed the corporate culture by implementing continuous innovation and measure-reward based business processes including; innovating and implementing process changes that increased product quality, shortened development cycles, and reduced time-to-market, delivering 4 major and 9 minor successive product releases with more features and functionality than originally specified, ahead of schedule and 20% under budget, driving the direction of BD for partnerships, OEM, licensing, and M&amp;A activity, improving product/service leadership through better alignment with Marketing, Pre/Post

Sales, and Prof Services, incorporating a Six Sigma based quality program to meet Government Common Criteria requirements, and developing a modified RUP/XP oriented development cycle to improve customer focus, management visibility, and efficiency.

Identified and developed core competencies to support the strategy and build the company&apos;s competitive advantage in the emerging value chain. Led design and architecture
changes to meet market objectives, improve the value proposition, and evolve the products towards enterprise scaleable mass market acceptance including; creating the first multi-gigabit IDS solution by doubling the performance of the ManHunt product line in under 4 months, adding High Availability and fail-over fault tolerance, improving clustering and cross node communication, adding VLAN specific policy, developing deep and shallow deception technology (ManTrap), developing the company&apos;s appliance strategy, and incorporating vulnerability assessment data during analysis.
 
Identified new product directions and market innovations (National Early Warning System, ZombieNet, Protocol Anomaly Pre-filtering, Post-event classification, etc.) and, authored and presented white papers at industry forums and Government assemblies (DARPA, DOJ, White House Office of Homeland Security, etc.) that resulted in sales negotiations including meetings with Tom Ridge, Homeland Security Director, and Richard Clarke, National Coordinator for Infrastructure Protection to design and develop a National Critical Infrastructure Protection plan based on Recourse&apos;s product offerings and future directions.
Initiated, led, and served as technical point of contact for all M&amp;A activity as well as sales, licensing, and partnership negotiations with over a dozen companies including Symantec, Microsoft, Network Associates, Cisco, Juniper, Check Point, Oracle, NetScreen, and Legato.

Successfully negotiated the $135 million acquisition of Recourse by Symantec (SYMC), the largest Information security company in the world, including making all initial contacts with Symantec&apos;s BD/Corp Dev department, the CTO, and business drivers, creating and presenting all material through the generation of the LOI, developing synergy and integration strategies, working with Investment Bankers to establish corporate valuation and combined value proposition, preparing, presenting, and directing all due diligence activity, and managing post acquisition integration.

Wrote RFIs/RFPs for all deals over a million dollars and architected customization work to meet customer requirements; all of which resulted in successful sales including a $30 million deal with the Navy/Marine Corps Intranet (NMCI); the IDS portion of largest Government procurement of digital security technology in history.</oa:Description>
							<UserArea>
								<ext:ProcessingComment>[*CO. NAME PROBABILITY = 4096; *POS. TITLE PROBABILITY = 658] [*Offset of farthest data found = 87]</ext:ProcessingComment>
							</UserArea>
						</PositionHistory>
					</EmployerHistory>
				</EmploymentHistory>
				<PersonQualifications>
					<PersonCompetency>
						<CompetencyID schemeID="Taxonomy 204" schemeAgencyID="SkillsRUs">023653</CompetencyID>
						<CompetencyName>VISUAL C++</CompetencyName>
						<LastUsedDate>2008</LastUsedDate>
						<ExperienceMeasure unitCode="Months">109</ExperienceMeasure>
						<UserArea>
							<ext:ProcessingComment>Found in WORK HISTORY</ext:ProcessingComment>
							<ext:TypeID>023653</ext:TypeID>
						</UserArea>
					</PersonCompetency>
					<PersonCompetency>
						<CompetencyID schemeID="Taxonomy 307" schemeAgencyID="SkillsRUs">005613</CompetencyID>
						<CompetencyName>Product Development</CompetencyName>
						<LastUsedDate>2007-05</LastUsedDate>
						<ExperienceMeasure unitCode="Months">66</ExperienceMeasure>
						<UserArea>
							<ext:ProcessingComment>Found in WORK HISTORY</ext:ProcessingComment>
							<ext:TypeID>005613</ext:TypeID>
						</UserArea>
					</PersonCompetency>
					<PersonCompetency>
						<CompetencyID schemeID="Taxonomy 199" schemeAgencyID="SkillsRUs">022909</CompetencyID>
						<CompetencyName>Project Manager</CompetencyName>
						<LastUsedDate>2007</LastUsedDate>
						<ExperienceMeasure unitCode="Months">234</ExperienceMeasure>
						<UserArea>
							<ext:ProcessingComment>Found in SUMMARY; WORK HISTORY</ext:ProcessingComment>
							<ext:TypeID>022909</ext:TypeID>
						</UserArea>
					</PersonCompetency>
				</PersonQualifications>				
			</ResourceProfile>
		</StaffingResource>
	</DataArea>
</ProcessStaffingResource>
<!--


Copyright The HR-XML Consortium. All Rights Reserved. http://www.hr-xml.org 
Copyright (c) 1997-2011 Open Applications Group, Inc. All Rights Reserved 
-->

